Love.
I say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
Yes, sir.
And God speak all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt out of the
house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me.
And showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shall not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy.
Six days shall thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy manservant, nor thy
maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother that thy
days may be long upon the land which the
Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house, thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbor's. I read Exodus 20
verses 1 through 17. May the Lord add a
blessing to the reading of this word. In
Jesus' name we pray. Amen. Amen. Amen.
So, here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions, as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your question so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But, let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother James.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Sean.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
program?
Yes, there are several held-over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Big
Brett says, "Could you please help me
understand the months? I read Esther 3:7
and I confused myself.
Isn't Abib the first month? I was trying
to show a friend that beginning of the
year is March or April according to
God."
All right. So, brother Julius there was
asking about this money and say they
read in the book of Esther, that book
right before Job. Shed some light,
brother.
Okay. Let's You are correct. Abib is the
first month. Let's go to the our
scripture.
Um
Brother James, let's go to
Esther the third chapter.
Now, what I want what what I want you to
know, Big Brett, is that
you have to understand the time.
Israel is in captivity under the Persian
Empire.
And the Persian Empire, just like the
Hebrew calendar, their calendar has 12
months. And so,
beginning what we call April
and ending in and ending being the first
month
Abib
or Nisan, which is the same month, and
ending in Adar,
which is March, okay? Esther 3 and verse
7.
Go ahead.
In the first In the first month, that is
the month Nisan, in the 12th year of
King Ahasuerus, they cast Pur, that is,
the lot, before Haman from day to day
and from month to month, to the 12th
month, that is, the month Adar.
Now,
Adar is the 12th month of what we call
uh
going into February, March, right? So,
now Israel is in captivity.
But, the calendar did not change. So,
now
Abib is the first month in the Hebrew
calendar and Nisan, which is still the
first month of the year in the
Babylonian calendar. Okay?
That's why it's called Nisan here. But,
now let's go to Exodus the 12th chapter.
And while we turn to Exodus the 10th
chapter, here's This is the our last
year's calendar, right? You can see it.
It says Adar, and then it goes into
Abib.
Okay? From the 12th month into the first
month of the year in the Hebrew
calendar, it's called Abib because when
Israel was in was not in uh captivity or
exiled out of the land, they called them
by the Hebrew names.
When they went into captivity under
Babylonians and then the Medo-Persians,
they went by their months, but they're
still different uh names, but it's still
the same number of months.
Exodus 12
Exodus 12, read verse 1 and 2. James, go
ahead.
And the Lord spake unto Moses and Aaron
in the land of Egypt, saying, "This
month shall be unto you the beginning of
months.
It shall be the first month of the year
to you."
Now, that's the first month of what we
call Abib. Let's confirm that. Go to the
13th chapter of Exodus.
And begin reading at verse 3 and 4.
Exodus 13, 3 and 4. Look what it's Look
what it's called because in the month of
Abib, we kept the we keep the Passover
in the 14th day of the first month at
evening is the Lord's Passover. On the
15th day is the feast of unleavened
bread.
And that is when after that Israel uh
uh uh we we got sprung out of Egypt. Go
ahead and verse three. Exodus 13 and
three, go ahead.
And Moses said unto the people,
"Remember this day, in which you came up
from Egypt out of the house of bondage.
For by strength of hand, the Lord
brought you out from this place. There
shall no leaven bread be eaten."
"This day came you out in the month
Abib." The first month.
So, Abib is the first month
in the Hebrew name. Nisan is the first
month under the Babylonian middle
Persian name, but it's still the first
month of the year in the March going to
April because
Rome came along and changed the
calendar. Okay? So, now you got January
being the first month, but that's not
the original calendar. So, now that's
the answer to the question. Nisan and
Abib is the same thing. So, Bib Brat,
you have to understand
it was called Nisan after the exile or
after the captivity, while they were in
captivity. Before they went into
captivity, they called them by their
Hebrew names, Abib. A- Abib and
um
But, if you look at
the Babylonian calendar, a lot of the
names
are similar to the Hebrew calendar.
Uh Tishri, the eighth month, and
Tishritu is is the Babylonian names. So,
on your own, you can do your own
research on the Babylonian calendar.
That's all I got, Cornell.
Messing with that phone up there?
What?
Nothing. I ain't messing with no phone.
All right. We're going to uh
say thank you, Julius, for that um
good light there. And um
we're going to continue to move on
until our next question.
Moving on, Linda Stringer says, "I'm new
to the IOG. I was curious if there was a
women's Bible study, and do women teach
other women at the IOG?"
All right. I'd like to say welcome to
the IOG. Glad to have you.
Uh guest caller.
The answer to both of them is no and no.
Mhm.
All right. So, there is no women's Bible
study, and to the women teaching other
women at the IOG, the answer is no to
both of those. So,
appreciate your question as we move on
to our next.
Next one, Victoria Smith asks, "In
Exodus 20:15,
thou shalt not steal. Can you explain
Proverbs 6:30?"
All right, brother Andre. Wish the world
kept that Exodus 20:15. Share some
light, brother. Yeah, Exodus 20 says
just that, "Thou shalt not steal." Now,
let's go to Proverbs 6 and read that. Uh
Proverbs 6, and we going to read verses
and 31.
Okay. Go ahead when you get it, brother
James.
Men do not despise a thief
if he steal to satisfy his soul when he
is hungry.
But if he be found, he shall restore
sevenfold.
He shall give all the substance of his
house.
Exactly. See, that other part is the
caveat
to a man stealing
to satisfy his whole his soul when he is
hungry. If he shall be found, he shall
restore sevenfold.
But let's look at something here. Let's
go to Leviticus 19.
Leviticus 19 and we're going to read
verses 9 and 10. Leviticus 19:9 and 10.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
Okay. It says, "And when you reap the
harvest of your land, thou shalt not
wholly reap the corners of thy field.
Neither shalt thou gather the gleanings
of thy harvest.
And thou shalt not glean the vineyard.
Neither shalt thou gather every grape of
thine vineyard.
Thou shalt leave them for the poor and
stranger. I am the Lord your God." See,
the Lord got something for the poor and
the stranger
that they can go and glean and eat as
much as they want to. Let's confirm
that. Go to Deuteronomy 23
and read verses 24 and 25.
Deuteronomy 23 verses 24 and 25. Go
ahead, brother.
When thou comest into thy neighbor's
vineyard, then thou mayest eat grapes
thy fill at thine own pleasure. But,
thou shalt not put any in thy vessel.
When thou comest into the standing corn
of thy neighbor, then thou mayest pluck
the ears with thine hand, but thou shalt
not move a sickle unto thy neighbor's
standing corn." See that? So, you can go
to your neighbor's standing corn. Uh if
you hungry, you can eat grapes to thy
fill. So, there's no reason to steal,
but you not to put none in your vessel
and you not to put a sickle upon his
corn.
So,
if you want to read further about that,
you on your own can go to Exodus 22
and read verses 1 through 15 and it'll
give you more detail about the
repercussions of stealing.
What and what happens behind that.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one. Barbara Steele says, "When
Satan seemed to be so comfortable
speaking with God about Job, was that
before he was cast down or after? And
who is under the chain of darkness right
now?"
All right. Well,
you you said that when Satan seemed to
be so comfortable, let's go into James 2
and 19.
James 2 and 19.
And we'll see how comfortable
he was.
Read that one verse for me, brother.
James 2 and 19.
Thou believest that there is one God.
Thou doest well. The devils also believe
and tremble.
So, I wouldn't say that was exactly
being comfortable, even though you are
having a conversation there. And then
you said, uh, "Speaking with God, was
that before he was cast down?" When you
say cast down, if you tell me cast out
of heaven,
um, that was way back
in the beginning before man was created.
So, you have to go way back further than
Job for that. Because when Adam and Eve
was created, Satan was already there.
So, but you asked, "And who is this
under chains of darkness?" Well, let's
go into that 2 Peter 2. 2 Peter 2.
And let's see who is this that's under
chains of darkness.
2 Peter 2.
And let's pick that up in verse
4. Cuz we just want you to understand
that the chains of darkness he can't
just appear before you.
He is under the chains of darkness to
not be able to appear before you. Second
Peter 2 and 4. Read that, bro.
For if God spared not the angels that
sinned, but cast them down to hell, and
delivered them into chains of darkness
to be reserved until judgment. Yeah, so
angels them evil angels under chains of
darkness. And you can't see them, and
they can't just show up before you.
And that's all I got. Anybody else want
to add?
All right. Want to say thank you. And
we're going to keep moving to our next
one.
Next one. Miss White
>> Also also Enoch Cornell.
Oh, yeah. Also Enoch. Correct.
All right.
Go ahead, Deborah.
Miss White wants you to explain 1
Corinthians 1 verse 25.
1 Corinthians 1 and 25, brother Jerome.
Um
let's go read it cuz I believe she's
talking about uh 1 Corinthians the first
chapter. Yeah.
Verse 25.
Yep.
Go ahead and read it when you get it.
Okay. Because the foolishness of God is
wiser than men, and the weakness of God
is stronger than men.
Yeah, the
um
Lord's wisdom is infinite, you know. And
uh the simple things, even the simple
things of God is way
over man's head. But uh can you read
that skip up and read that verse 21 for
me?
Okay.
For after that, in the wisdom of God,
the world by wisdom knew not God.
It pleased God by the foolishness of
preaching to save them that believe.
Yeah, by the foolishness of preaching,
the Lord is
teaching us how to
get salvation. Okay.
Uh
uh
I also want to hit it from another
angle.
Uh
uh
the foolishness of God when it said the
foolishness of God
uh is wiser
than than men, I was thinking of I was
thinking about like in in Egypt
when the Lord had Israel to leave Egypt
and come through to to the wilderness to
the Red Sea, I can imagine them
Israelites were saying,
"Why you bringing to to this Red Sea?"
You know, especially when they saw them
Egyptians coming after them. They're
like, "Where else we going to go?" They
don't have They didn't have no idea the
Lord was going bring them Egyptians to
that through that Red Sea to drown every
last one of them. So, that might have
been foolishness to them, but that
wisdom of God, he knew what he was
doing, you know. But, that's that's all
I wanted to say about that.
Mhm.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on.
Moving on. Be alert asks in Zephaniah
2:12-13,
"Are there any scriptures that helps
give understanding as why Ethiopia will
be slain? And in verse 13, has this
prophecy of Assyria been fulfilled?"
All right. So, they want to know some
about that Zephaniah, which is that book
right before Haggai. And brother Jerome,
Yeah, um
let's go and read it, but both them
verses know, those are going to be
future events. It's you know, we're
going to tie the first chapter and the
third chapter
to it to show that to you. All right,
but let's go read the verses.
Okay. Zephaniah 2 and and 12 says,
"Ye Ethiopians also, ye shall be slain
by my sword.
And he will stretch out his hand against
the north and destroy Assyria and will
make Nineveh a desolation
and dry like a wilderness.
Yeah. And if you just read the all of
Zephaniah, it's only three chapters.
The Lord going to destroy the all the
wicked,
you know, from all
of all the nations. He going, you know,
so but let's
go to that first chapter
and read verse 14 through 18.
Okay.
It says,
"The great day of the Lord is near, it
is near and hastened greatly.
Even the voice of the day of the Lord,
the mighty man shall cry there bitterly.
That day is a day of wrath,
a day of trouble and distress, a day of
wasteness and desolation, a day of
darkness and gloominess, a day of clouds
and thick darkness. Mhm.
>> A
A day of the trumpet and alarm against
the fenced cities and against the high
towers.
And I will bring distress upon men that
they shall walk like blind men because
they have sinned against the Lord. And
their blood shall be poured out as dust
and their flesh as the dung.
Neither their silver nor their gold
shall be able to deliver them in the day
of the Lord's wrath.
But the whole land shall be devoured by
the fire of his jealousy.
For he shall make even a speedy riddance
of all them that dwell in the land.
Yeah, and um
two more verses chapter 3 verse verse 8
and 9 that'll be it.
3 verse 8. Okay, chapter 3 verse 8 and 9
says,
"Therefore, wait ye upon me, saith the
Lord, until the day that I rise up to
the pray.
For my determination is to gather the
nations, that I may assemble the
kingdoms, to pour upon them my
indignation, even all my fierce anger.
For all the earth shall be devoured with
the fire of my jealousy. Yeah. For then
will I turn to the people a pure
language, that they may all be up
I'm sorry. For then will I turn to the
people a pure language, that they may
all call upon the name of the Lord to
serve him with one consent. Yeah.
And that's all I got.
All right, thank you for that, brother,
cuz we know all the silver and gold
can't buy you away from the wrath of the
Lord.
Yeah, I think I think there's a
scripture, I'm trying to remember,
there's a scripture where the
the Ethiopians did something to Israel.
I don't know if it was in the days of
Asa, but the Lord is paying them back
for that, too. Yeah.
Yeah.
He's a God that don't forget.
All right.
Let's continue to move on. Sister
Deborah, what's our next question?
>> Moving on.
Lion of Judah says, "Before the seven
vials of God's wrath is poured on Earth
by his angels, will people be able to
see Christ in the cloud sitting on his
throne before he enters Earth?
All right. So, before the seven vials of
wrath is poured out, will people be able
to see Christ in the cloud sitting on
his throne? Guest caller.
Yes.
Let's go to Revelation the 6th chapter.
Read 12 through 17.
Okay.
Revelation 6: 12 through 17 says,
"And I beheld when he had opened the
sixth seal, and lo, there was a great
earthquake, and the sun became black as
sackcloth of hair, and the moon became
as blood."
"And the seventh stars of heaven fell
into the earth, even as a fig tree
casteth her untimely figs when she is
shaken of a mighty wind." Yeah, and the
stars of heaven fell.
"And the stars of heaven fell, excuse
me, upon the earth, even as a fig tree
casteth her untimely figs when she is
shaken of a mighty wind."
"And the heaven departed as departed as
a scroll when it is rolled together, and
every mountain and island were moved out
of their places."
Now, right there.
Mhm.
>> Heaven is a scroll as a scroll.
That means just going to roll back. Now,
once that roll back,
then people will be able to see the Lord
sitting on the throne. Now, that's why
they're going to go through this
reaction. Keep reading.
"And the kings of the earth, and the
great men, and the rich men, and the
chief captains, and the mighty men, and
every bondman, and every free man hid
themselves in the dens and in the rocks
of the mountains."
"And said to the mountains and rocks,
fall on us
and hide us from the face of him that
sitteth on the throne and from the wrath
of the lamb.
Now, that's why that's why that lets you
know that they saw him.
They said, you know, fall on us
hide us
from the face of him that sits on the
throne, sitting on the throne and from
the wrath of the lamb.
So, they can see him. Once that heaven
rolls back, everybody can see him.
Finish there.
For the great day of his wrath is come
and who shall be able to stand?
Now,
and he's going to they're going to be
looking at him for a long time.
A minimum of 5 months.
And they're going to see him when he get
up and start his descent. Yeah, they'll
be able to see him for a long time, at
least for 5 months, probably a little
more.
That's all that I have to say.
All right.
Um make sure you're on the right side
when he show up.
All right.
Hope that answered your question, Naz.
We continue to move on.
Moving on. After my solo ones
explanation on John 4:17
and 18. What did the Lord mean telling
her, and he whom thou now has is not thy
husband? When she met the Lord, she had
a man, but not her husband. Explain.
All right. Brother Jerome.
Let's go read the verse.
John, the fourth chapter, verse 17 and
18.
Okay.
It says,
the woman answered and said, I have no
husband.
Jesus said unto her, "Thou hast well
said, I have no husband.
For thou has had five husbands, and he
whom thou now has is not thy husband,
and that says thou truly."
Yeah.
Uh, nowadays
the women kind of call them their
boyfriends.
But they ain't married to them.
Okay?
Uh
But that's not a husband, you know.
Even though people call them boyfriends,
okay? But um
To to understand further, uh verse 17
and 18, when he said, you know, "Well,
thou has had five husbands, okay? Uh
Well,
not at the same time, okay? All right.
So, you know. But if Lord said she had
five husbands, that mean there was a
time where she had a husband, and then
for whatever reason, he he died or
whatever the case may be, she had a
second, third, fourth, and fifth
husband. Okay?
Uh they might have died, who knows? All
right. But the Lord know.
But that's all I got on it.
Well, you know, I'm not going to answer
them.
Okay. That's fine.
And that And that killed that old theory
that some heathens was running around
saying, "If you sleep with a woman, that
is your she is your wife." Okay.
>> a lie everything.
Mhm. That just cleared it up right
there. You didn't have five husbands.
The one that you have is not your
husband. The one you have now. I'm sure
they were sleeping together.
What What What the Bible call that?
Fornication.
>> Fornication. There you go. Mhm. Yeah.
Yeah.
Thank supposed to let you know. If
somebody come to you coming when a when
a man lay with a woman that's his wife,
that is a
lie.
Mhm.
Cuz Jesus would have told this woman
Look, you got six husbands now cuz you
done laid with this one. Yeah. Right.
Yeah.
Yeah. That Can Can you Can we go to that
Romans 7:1-2
kind of back up what Guest Column
is saying?
Romans 7 Yeah, Romans 7:1-2.
Romans 7:1-2
says
Know ye not, brethren? For I speak to
them that know the law.
How that the law hath dominion over a
man as long as he liveth.
For the woman which hath an husband is
bound by the law to her husband so long
as he liveth. But if the husband be
dead, she is loose from the law of her
husband. Yeah, you know.
So
That That's all I've got.
All right.
Read on down about fornication. Okay.
So keep reading?
Oh, no. That's not Romans. Go to 1
Corinthians, the 7th chapter, and start
at 1.
Okay.
1 Corinthians chapter 7 verse 1 says
Now concerning the things whereof ye
wrote unto me it is good for a man not
to touch a woman.
Nevertheless, to avoid fornication
let every man have his own wife
and let every woman have her own
husband.
Now, if you are not married, you are a
fornicator. Mhm.
Mhm. Keep reading.
Think it's about about seven ways they
It is What it says it's it's better to
marry than to burn.
>> Verse 9.
Verse 9. Read it.
It says, "But if they cannot contain,
let them marry. For it is better to
marry than to burn." Mhm. Okay.
It lets you know that because you're
living with a woman, sleeping with a
woman, that don't mean that's your wife.
Yeah. You're fornicating.
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't want no part of that.
You're married five times, but then one
that that sixth guy you wasn't married
to, that means she was fornicating with
him. Mhm. Yes, sir.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Moving on. Sky Rider says, "We get that
the righteous make the first
resurrection and wicked that dies in
their sins go to the lake of fire."
What would qualify a person at the
second resurrection to
to still scarcely make it?
All right. Brother Julius.
Let's go to Revelation the 20th chapter
for that answer.
Revelation 20, James, and we going to
read verse We're going to start at verse
6.
Okay.
The Lord is a just God. He's a fair God.
And his judgments are All his judgments
are righteous. Revelation 20:6. Go
ahead.
Blessed and holy is he that hath part in
the first resurrection. On such the
second death hath no power.
But they shall be priests of God and of
Christ and shall reign with him 1,000
years. And that's why the the dead in
Christ and the righteous living
that's the reward of those who died in
Christ and those who are part of the
first resurrection. And those who are
changed, who are righteous at his
coming. Back up and read verse 5. Go
ahead.
But the rest of the dead lived not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection. So now,
you're blessed if you're in the first
resurrection. Now, you ain't in the
first resurrection, you got to come up
in the great white throne judgment. Skip
down to verse 11. Go ahead.
And I saw a great white throne and him
that sat on it from whose face the earth
and the heaven fled away.
And there was found no place for them.
Uh-huh.
And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God. And the books were
opened.
And another book was opened, which is
the book of life. And the dead were
judged out of those things which were
written in the books according to their
works. Now, this is all the people that
weren't in the first resurrection, okay?
So,
they got to be judged.
Go ahead.
And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it. And death and hell delivered up
the dead which were in them. Uh-huh. And
they And they were judged every man
according to their works. Go ahead. And
death and hell were cast into the lake
of fire. This is the second death. Now,
how you how you going to make it? Go
ahead and read.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire. So now, what if you are found
in the Lamb's Book of Life?
You made it.
You made it through the great white
throne judgment. So the answer is
your name have to be written in the last
book of life the last book of life at
the second resurrection.
That's all I got Cornell.
All right. Yes, sir. Thank you for that.
Everybody on this panel is shooting for
that first resurrection. Please come and
join us. That's right. Strive strive.
Strive for that first fight for that
first resurrection. That's it, brother.
Yes, sir.
All right. Hope that answered your
question with a time check.
Yes, the time is 8:06.
Joseph asked, "Why is there an
inconsistency with Matthew 1:13
and 1 Chronicles 3:19
and 20?
Who is Abihud?
Zerubbabel had no son by that name."
All right, brother Julius. They start
off in Matthew 1:13 then they skip to
Chronicles 3 1 Chronicles 3:19 and 20.
Share some light, brother. Okay, first
of all, we got to understand
there
it is more than one person with that
name in the Bible. There's no
inconsistencies in the Bible. Only thing
that we have not known, been taught, or
understood.
There are no inconsistencies in the The
Bible is a very consistent. It's just
that we have to have proper
understanding and proper teaching. Now,
uh
let's read that scripture. Matthew 1:13
James, go ahead and read it.
And Zerubbabel begat Abihud. Hold on
James. Hold on. Hold on. There's a
difference. Watch this. Start at verse 1
then we'll skip to verse 13. Okay.
The book of the generation of Jesus
Christ, the son of David, the son of
Abraham.
Now go to verse 13. This is the
genealogy
of the main people that came through
genealogy Jesus genealogy. Go ahead and
read 13 now.
And Zerubbabel begat Abiud. And Abiud
begat Eliakim. And Eliakim begat Azor.
Now.
Now, now let's go to that 1 Chronicles 3
and 19.
So we can get some understanding and
we're going to show you one more place
where where the same name is mentioned,
but it doesn't mean they have to be the
the same person. Go ahead and read at
that verse that that verse 19 and 20 1
Chronicles
3 19 and 20. Go ahead.
And the sons of Pedaiah were Zerubbabel
and Shimei. And the sons of Zerubbabel
Meshullam and Hananiah and Shelomith
their sister.
And
and Hashubah and Ohel and Berechiah and
Hasadiah and
Jesheab has has [clears throat] said
five.
So
just to show you this but when you read
this right here, this does not
now back I'm going to read verse one.
See these are the peoples and the and
their children and their children's
children. It's a genealogy. Go ahead.
Now these were the sons of David which
were born unto him in Hebron. The first
the firstborn Amnon of Hanoam the
Jezreelitess
the second Daniel of Abigail the
Carmelitess.
So it just goes on and on, but it does
not mean it's the same person. Let's go
back to Genesis and give you one more
example that that's better even better
understanding. Genesis chapter 10.
Because the book tell you of Noah's
three sons was the whole earth
overspread.
Let
me see here. Hold on a minute.
Genesis
Yep, Genesis back up and read Genesis
chapter 5, not 10. Genesis chapter 5.
Okay.
And when you get it, read verse 18. Now,
these
and this is in the in the genealogy of
Adam.
And Adam and uh
Go ahead at verse 18.
And Jared lived 162
years and he begat Enoch. So now, but
verse 1 tells you that this is the
genealogy
of generations of Adam in the day that
God created man and in likeness of God.
So this is the generation of Adam.
Adam had Cain. Now, go to Genesis
chapter
Because these guys Cain had a son, too.
Where am I? Genesis Cain had a son.
And he was disinherited.
And he had a son named Enoch.
But it's not the same it's not the same
Enoch.
I wrote it down. I wrote it down here.
Uh this is chapter
What chapter?
Yeah, yeah, it looks like 4 and 17,
Julius.
>> Yeah.
Yep, 4 and 17.
It says, "And Cain knew his wife and she
conceived and bare Enoch, and he builded
a city and called the name of the city
after the name of his son Enoch.
Two different people from two different
lineages, one from Adam and one from
Cain. Cain is disinherited, but yet two
different people with two different
names.
With the same name, I'm sorry.
With the same name because that's the
way the law works because
you they all kinfolk. All of them come
out of Noah's son Shem, Ham, and
Japheth. And sometimes you can read in
each one of them lineages, they have
people that have the same name.
That's why you have to understand
uh uh the question uh uh
no inconsistencies. It's just you have
to have understanding how the Bible
reads, who's who
uh in their time frame.
I hope that helped.
Yes, sir. Indeed. It's like people
surname their selves today, right,
Julius? Just like uh you got uh Judas
that betrayed Jesus.
But then you have another Judas.
You know, you have uh uh
who was called one of his disciples. Uh
uh you have uh
different people that Simon son of.
That's where they identify people that
had the same name.
Yeah.
James and then James the less. That's
all I got.
All right. Thank you for that as we move
on to our next question.
Moving on. Linda Stringer says, "You
have taught
that [clears throat] angels
are called men in the Bible sometimes.
Did Jacob wrestle with man or an angel
in Genesis 32?"
All right. I know Linda you said that
you was new. Well, we just want you and
all the other viewers to understand that
we read first.
We read the words and then we teach and
expound from there. Oh, yeah, that is
correct. That sometime angels are called
men in the Bible. We answered that last
week, but let's see cuz you asked did
Jacob wrestle with a man or an angel in
Genesis 32. Let's go to that Genesis 32.
And it's going to say
Let's read it.
Genesis 32, brother, and I want you to
pick it up at that verse 24.
Okay.
Go right ahead.
And Jacob was left alone, and there
wrestled a man with him until the
breaking of the day.
Mhm.
And when he saw that he prevailed not
against him, he touched the hollow of
his thigh, and a hollow of Jacob's thigh
was out of joint as he wrestled with
him. And a man, if he touch your thigh,
won't take it out of joint. That's
right.
>> Let's uh continue continue to read.
And he said, "Let me go, for the day
breaketh." And he said, "I will not let
thee go, except thou bless me." Mhm.
And he said unto him, "What is thy
name?" And he said, "Jacob."
And he said, "Thy name shall be called
no more Jacob, but Israel. For as a
prince has thou power with God and with
man and has prevailed."
Oh, yeah.
And Jacob asked him and said, "Tell me,
I pray thee, thy name." And he said,
"Wherefore is it that thou doest ask
after my name?" And he blessed him
there.
And Jacob called the name of the place
Peniel, for I have seen God face to face
and my life is preserved. This this was
an angel here, and Jacob would not have
told another man, "Hey, I have seen God
face to face unless he knew that this
was an angel he was dealing with because
he was looking for a blessing." Now,
turn back quickly
to Genesis 25, and I just want to read
this and tie it in to showing that that
was an angel in our next script. Genesis
25, and pick read 24 through 26 for me.
Okay.
It says, "And when her days to be
delivered were fulfilled, behold, there
were twins in her womb." This is the
same Jacob, and this is Rebecca who was
having
her children here, which were twins.
Read.
And the first came out red, all over,
like an hairy garment. And they called
his name Esau.
Yeah. And after that came his brother
out, and his hand took hold on Esau's
heel, and his name was called Jacob. And
Isaac was three score years old when she
bare him. And I wanted to read I wanted
to read that because it said, "And Jacob
took hold on Esau's heel."
And now, let's go into Hosea
and bring it to a close right here.
Let's go into Hosea 12.
Because we're going to read about the
heel right here. This is the same Jacob,
same Esau we just read in that Genesis.
Hosea 12, and read that verse 3 and 4,
and let's see if that man that Jacob
wrestled with if it's clarified right
here in verse 4. Read 3 and 4, brother.
He took his brother by the heel in the
womb, and by his strength he had power
with God. You read that. Go ahead.
Yea, he had power over the angel and
prevailed.
He wept and made supplication unto him.
He found him in Bethel, and there he
spake with us. So, right here in Hosea,
it tells us that he was wrestling with
an angel. Does it say, "Yea, he had
power over the angel." So, that was an
angel that Jacob was wrestling with in
that Genesis
20 uh 32 that you had asked us about.
And that's all I got.
We hope that answered your question.
We're going to move on to our next one.
Next one, Cresia asks, "When women watch
a lesson online,
should we have our heads covered?"
When women watch a lesson online,
Brother Dre, what should they do?
They should have their heads covered,
but let's go to uh 1 Corinthians 11.
1 Corinthians 11, and we're going to
start at verse
let's see.
1 Corinthians 11,
and let's start at uh
verse 1. Read 1 and 2.
Okay.
It says,
"Be ye followers of me, even as I also
am of Christ. Mhm. Now, I praise you,
brethren, that you remember me in all
things and keep the ordinances as I
delivered them unto you." He said, "Keep
the ordinances as I delivered them unto
you." And he said, "Follow me as I
follow Christ."
Skip down.
Well, go ahead. Read down to 6, man,
from 3 to 6. Go ahead.
Verse 3 says, "But I would have you know
that the head of every man is Christ,
and the head of the woman is the man,
and the head of Christ is God."
Go ahead. Every man praying or
prophesying having his head covered
dishonoreth his head. Mhm. But every
woman that prayeth or prophesyeth
with her head uncovered dishonoreth her
head.
For that is even all one as if she were
shaven. So so if a woman praying or
prophesying
has her head uncovered, she dishonoreth
her head.
It's as if she were shaven or
prophesying, but why is he saying this?
Skip down and read
verse 10.
For this cause ought the woman to have
power on her on her head because of the
angels. And this angel is talking about
the fallen angel.
Because the fallen angel in the garden
deceived Eve.
And she fell for it. Now, let's look at
something else. Let's go to Ephesians
the sixth chapter.
And I want you to read verse 11.
Ephesians 6
and verse 11. Go ahead when you get it,
brother.
Put on the whole armor of God that ye
may be able to stand against the wiles
of the devil. So you got to have on the
whole armor of God to stand against the
wiles of the devil.
Skip down and read verse
17 and 18.
And take the helmet of salvation and the
sword of the spirit, which is the word
of God. Listen, the word of God is what
you need to obey and live by. And we
just read in the word of God that if a
man have his head covered, he
dishonoreth his head. And if a woman has
her head
uh uncovered, she dishonors her head.
And if you praying or prophesying, or
you in the presence, you are entreating
the Lord for understanding.
When you there, you open up with prayer.
You close with a prayer. So, yes, you
should have your head covered.
Verse 18, brother. Go ahead.
Praying always with all prayer and
supplication in the spirit, and watching
thereunto with all perseverance and
supplication for all saints.
>> Say praying always. Hey,
always praying. You know, so you always
seeking the Lord. So, you want to do
that, sister, especially if you are in
the word of God and dealing with the
word of God. I'm not I'mma just mention
this. Numbers five talks about
a woman having uh being suspected of
cheating on her husband.
And the first thing that they do
when they pour this
this this solution on her that would rot
her stomach if she is found guilty
is they uncover her head.
That's what it says in the scripture.
And the reason why it says that is
because the sister's head is covered.
That's all I got.
That's it. That's Numbers five.
You could read it on your own, 18 to 30.
Mhm.
Yeah.
Yeah. All right, brother. Thank you for
that.
As we continue to move on to our next
one.
Moving on. Skywriter
"Are the two witnesses two literal
people or a group?"
I read in Revelation 11:3-4
about the two witnesses being the two
olive trees, but when I read Jeremiah
11:16-17,
it has olive tree and also mentioned
Israel and Judah.
Okay. Uh Brother Jerome, was it two
witnesses or a group?
No, it's it's it's two individuals
in that uh Revelations 11. Um
but let's go read it. Revelations
11:3-4.
Okay.
Revelation 11:3-4
says,
"And I will give power unto my two
witnesses, and they shall prophesy 1,260
days clothed in sackcloth.
These are the two olive trees and the
two candlesticks standing before the God
of the earth." [clears throat]
Okay. Yeah, these two uh individual
uh men. They're not Moses and Elijah
that everybody want to say they're Moses
and Elijah. They're not none of the uh
patriarchs at all that have uh
died, you know, uh but let's go, you
know, they but they're going to be flesh
and blood men. Two flesh and blood men,
okay? We don't know who they're going
who they are though, but they're two
flesh and blood men. But let's go to uh
uh Zechariah chapter 4
and read verse 11 and 12.
Zechariah chapter 4
verses 11 and 12 says,
"Then answered I and said unto him, What
are these two olive trees upon the right
side of the candlestick and upon the
left side thereof?"
"And I answered again and said unto him,
What be these two olive branches which
through the two golden pipes empty the
golden oil out of themselves?"
>> Yeah, so he called them two olive
branches, not a group of olive branches,
two.
So, there's two individuals. And if you
uh if we was to go back to uh
Revelations and read uh the 11th chapter
verse 7 and 8, these two olive
trees mentioned there,
uh they're going to get killed. Yeah.
Okay?
And so, they they're not spirit beings
and all like that. They're flesh and
blood men. They're going to get killed
and then they're going to make the first
resurrection. Okay? Now, uh um
you also uh talked about that uh
Jeremiah.
>> Jeremiah, yeah. Jeremiah, let's look at
that next. Jeremiah 11 verse 16 and 17.
Okay. Yeah. And I also want to add them
them two olive um
trees mentioned,
them two witnesses,
we know they're going to be Israelites.
And the reason why we know cuz the Lord
was said I I
uh he said
to the children of Israel, "Ye are my
witnesses." So, we know them two
witnesses are going to be Israelites,
okay?
All right. Now, let's deal with that uh
Jeremiah 11 verse 16 and 17.
It says,
"The Lord called thy name a green olive
tree,
fair, and of goodly fruit. With the
noise of a great tumult, he hath kindled
fire upon it. And the branches of it are
broken.
Mhm. For the Lord of hosts that planted
thee has pronounced evil against thee
for the evil of the house of Israel and
of the house of Judah, which they have
done against themselves to provoke me to
anger in offering incense unto Baal.
Yeah. Now,
that is talking about
uh
the children of Israel, the 12 tribes,
okay? Uh and
can you read that 15 Read that 15 for
me?
Okay.
What hath my beloved to do in mine
house? Seeing she has wrought lewdness
with many, and the holy flesh is passed
from thee.
When thou doest evil, them thou
rejoicest. Yeah, he's talking about his
people, the children of the Israel,
which he called a
uh olive tree. Okay? Now, let's let's
tie that with the Romans.
Romans 11 chapter.
Where he talks about his people there
that he referred to as a olive tree
there. Romans 11
and verse 17 through 21.
Okay. It says, "And if some of the
branches be broken off, and thou being a
wild olive tree were grafted in among
them, and with them partakest of the
root and fatness of the olive tree,
boast not against the branches. But if
thou boast, thou bearest not the root,
but the root thee.
Thou wilt say then, 'The branches were
broken off that I might be grafted in.'"
And he's talking about the the
Israelites. They are the branches of the
olive tree. Okay. When you say that it
was broken off, well, they were broken
off because of unbelief.
But, go ahead.
Well, because of unbelief, they were
broken off. And thou standest by faith.
But, not high-minded, but fear.
For if God spared not the natural
branches, take heed lest he also spare
not thee. Mhm.
That's all I got on it.
Yeah.
All right. Thank you for that as we move
on to our next question.
Next one. Kim Noel asks, is Satan God's
adversary?
I know God uses Satan as a servant, but
is he also his adversary?
She says, Satan is a god of this world,
and if we're a friend of this world, we
are enemy to God. And in Matthew 16:3,
it says, get thee behind me, Satan. Thou
art an offense to me. And in 14:13,
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God. And Satan end will be the lake
of fire.
All right. So,
yes, Carla.
Um,
looks like that Matthew 16:3 has nothing
to do with what they put in that
question, but can you take it from
there?
Matthew 16:23.
And 23. All right.
And Matthew 16:23 says,
but he turned and said unto Peter, get
thee behind me, Satan.
Thou art an offense unto me.
For thou savorest not the things that be
of God, but those that be of men."
Now, what we got to do is find out tell
you why
that uh
the Lord said that
to Peter, "Okay?"
Yeah.
>> Let's Let's Let's back up to
uh uh
uh
verse 21.
We're going to read that and do it.
Okay.
Verse 21 says,
"From that time forth began Jesus to
show unto his disciples how that he must
go unto Jerusalem and suffer many things
of the elders and chief priests and
scribes and be killed and be raised
again the third day."
Now, he was telling them about his death
and resurrection. But let's see what
what Peter said. Go ahead.
"Then Peter took him and began to rebuke
him, saying, 'Be it far from thee, Lord.
This shall not be unto thee.'"
Mhm.
All right. Now, he
>> But he He going to rebuke He going to
rebuke the Lord. You understand?
Yeah. Oh, Lord, this ain't going to
happen.
And then that's what the Lord said what
he said. Go ahead.
"But he turned and said unto Peter, 'Get
thee behind me, Satan. Thou art an
offense unto me. For thou savorest not
the things that be of God, but those
that be of men.'"
So, that's why he said it. Because uh
like he had told the Jews in in in in in
in other places, he said, "You know, you
are your
father, the devil. Because after your
father you will do.
So when the Lord say going something
going to happen and you rebuke him,
then you are in the spirit of Satan.
Yeah. If it come out of Jesus' mouth, I
don't care what you how you feel, you
ain't supposed to rebuke him because he
know that he can't lie. Mhm.
So
Peter
in his
I say uh so-called compassion for the
Lord
allowed Satan to use him.
Cuz he rebuked the Lord.
Yeah.
Now as for the uh uh uh uh
uh
the other about the Lord the uh uh
his uh
What did it say about the adversary?
Read that again.
Yes, is Satan's adversary.
She says, I know God uses Satan as a
servant, but is he also his adversary?
Of course he is.
Because he's the adversary to God's
creation. He tried to kill murder the
whole creation.
I want to show you.
That mean that he's our adversary and
then if he is our adversary, he's God's
adversary.
First Peter the fifth chapter and read
verse eight.
First Peter the fifth chapter and verse
eight says,
"Be sober, be vigilant because your
adversary the devil as a roaring lion
walketh about seeking whom he may
devour."
Yeah. Yeah.
So he's man's adversary.
And what did the Lord say concerning
the adversary
uh to us?
Let's go to Exodus the 23rd chapter and
read verse 22.
Exodus 23 and verse 22 says,
"But if thou shalt indeed obey his
voice, and do all that I speak, then I
will be an enemy unto thine enemies, and
an adversary unto thine adversaries."
Who now?
Satan is God's adversary and God and uh
Because he wanted to destroy the whole
creation. So of course he's his
adversary.
But then he also he is a ministering
spirit. That means God uses him too when
he want him.
That's when he need when he need
somebody to go upside your head.
Yes, sir. That's all I have to say.
All right.
Thank you for that.
Sister Deborah, are we walking into new
territory?
Uh yes, we are. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday,
January the 7th, 2026.
Shayne Aquilla Akujobi asks,
"Were the three men
who approached Abraham in Genesis 18:2
angels in human form? And also, when the
Lord is mentioned in the Old Testament,
is that the Father or Jesus speaking?"
All right. Let's go to that Genesis
18:2.
That was the first question.
Yes.
And let's pick it up at that verse one.
We'll go open it up to the panel. And
they wanted to know, again, Deborah,
about these three men.
Right. Were they angels in human forms?
All right. Let's pick it up at that one,
brother.
Go ahead, guest caller.
When you say 18 and 22?
18 and
>> 18 18 and 2, sir. Two.
18 and 2, read it.
Read one, James. Okay.
And the Lord appeared unto him in the
plains of Mamre, and he sat in the tent
door in the heat of the day.
And he lifted up his eyes and looked,
and lo,
three men stood by him. And when he saw
them, he ran to meet them from the tent
door, and bowed himself towards the
ground.
Now, let you know, they was three men.
And how many of them was angels?
We going to see.
Skip down to verse
10.
Okay.
Verse 10 says,
No, maybe hold on a minute. Hold on.
>> Okay.
Let's uh
skip down to verse 17, cuz the Lord was
going down there to destroy Sodom and
Gomorrah.
Do here.
And the Lord said, "Shall I hide from
Abraham that thing which I do?
Do here. Seeing that Abraham shall
surely become a great mighty nation, and
all the nations of the earth shall be
blessed in him.
Mhm.
For I know him that he will command his
children and his household after him,
and they shall keep the way of the Lord
to do justice and judgment, that the
Lord may bring upon Abraham that which
he had spoken of him."
Now, so Abraham, so then the Lord
started to speak with Abraham. In fact,
Abraham started to bargain with God.
Okay?
Yep. And uh uh uh uh
Well, skip down
verse 22.
Keep reading.
Okay, verse 21 says, "I will go down now
and see whether they have done
altogether according to the cry of it
which has come unto me and if not, I
will know."
And the And the men turned their faces
from thence and went towards Sodom but
Abraham stood yet before the Lord.
Now you see it's the two men that went
to
Sodom, those are angels.
But the third one was the Lord, that's
why I said and Abraham stayed with He
stood there with the Lord and started to
try and bargain. If there's so many
people where you sit not destroy.
Okay?
The one was God
and the other two was angels but all of
them looked like men to Abraham.
Yes, sir.
Yeah, all right.
All right.
>> And And the other question was when the
Lord is mentioned in the Old Testament,
is that the Father or Jesus speaking?
Go to 1 Corinthians 10 chapter and start
reading at verse 1.
1 Corinthians 10 and verse 1 says,
"Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye
should be ignorant how that all our
fathers were under the cloud and all
passed through the sea
and were all baptized unto Moses in the
cloud and in the sea and did eat did all
eat the same spiritual meat and did all
drink the same spiritual drink. For they
drank of that spiritual rock that
followed them and that rock was Christ.
It lets you know
that was Jesus in the cloud that led
them in the wilderness.
And also, there was Jesus that brought
them across through the Red Sea.
So, Jesus is the one that struck them.
Jesus is the one that gave you the
commandments. He gave the dietary law.
He gave it all cuz he was the God of the
Old Testament. Go into St. John 5 and
read verse 37.
Okay.
John 5 and and 37
says,
"And the Father himself, which has sent
me, hath borne witness of me. Ye have
neither heard his voice at any time, nor
seen his shape."
Anytime covers all times.
Yes, it does.
And we will not see or hear the voice of
the Father until New New Jerusalem come
down.
And then, you will not be man. You will
be God. That's why Jesus said, "I am
Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the
end, the first and the last." He's the
first God that we saw in his flesh and
blood form, and he's going to be the
last God that we see in his
flesh and blood form. So, when we see
the Father God the Father, we will not
be flesh and blood. We will be God. Yes,
sir. In that order.
That's it. That's all I'm going to say.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one. Next one. Zion
asked, "Could you explain Psalms 90
verse 10? Someone said it means we are
only given 70 years, and if we are not
sick, he gives us more time."
All right. Psalms 90
and 10.
Let's go there and read that, brother,
because, hey, extension of time, yeah,
we know God control that at all times.
Psalms 90 and 10, go right ahead.
The days of our years are three score
years and 10.
And if by reason of strength, they be
fourscore years, yet is their strength
labor and sorrow. For it is soon cut off
and we fly away.
Mhm. Question behind that again,
Deborah.
Uh they stayed.
Uh someone said it means we only are
given 70 years and if we are not sick,
he'll give us more time.
Has nothing to do with being sick. Has
something to do with the mercy and the
promise of the Lord. You got people that
that's a hundred and some years old
still around.
Mhm. Mhm.
But God said an average
of uh 70 and by the way, but before he
said an average,
he said and let's go to Genesis the
sixth chapter show you something here.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Genesis 6 and starting reading at verse
one.
Okay.
Genesis 6 and 1 says,
And it came to pass when men began to
multiply on the face of the earth and
daughters were born unto them, that the
sons of God saw the daughters of men
that they were fair. And they took them
wives of all which they chose. Mhm.
And the Lord said, "My spirit shall not
always strive with man. For that he also
is flesh, yet his days shall be 120
years.
So, now there, he cut him down from
immortal uh uh from a whole from 7 8 900
years to 120.
But then later on, he said the average
is 70, but if by reason of the strength,
he can go to 80.
Mhm. But still, he didn't remove the
120.
We just saw where a lady in New York
just lived to be 122.
But the average year, he cut it down to
70 years. But before that,
he cut it down to 120.
So, still you got those years that you
can live in between at the mercy of the
Lord. That's all I have to say.
That's right.
Being sick or not don't always determine
long life.
No, uh-uh. Some people real healthy.
>> [clears throat]
>> He end up
having a heart attack and one nothing
wrong with their heart.
That's right.
Yeah.
All right. I hope that answered your
question now.
With a time check as we keep going,
Sister Daphne.
Yes, the time is 8:45.
Uh Fire Girl asked, "Can a woman divorce
a husband who cheats?"
Can a woman divorce a husband who
cheats?
Open to the panel.
Yes, caller.
Can a woman divorce a husband if he
cheats?
I'm going to let her take that to the
Lord.
All right.
Thing I will say,
if only thing I will say is if you got a
husband that's cheating, he is not a
servant of God, okay?
And let's go through it one little
thing. Let's go in the 1 Corinthians the
7th chapter.
So, if he's a cheater, he's a
non-believer.
Mhm.
And we want to point out something here.
All right.
It is uh
It's on uh
And the woman which hath an husband that
believeth not, you want to start there?
That's where we going to start it. Mhm.
Okay. All right. Verse 13.
It says,
"And the woman which hath an husband
that believeth not, and if he be pleased
to dwell with her, let her not leave
him."
"For the unbelieving husband
Did you want me to finish that, sir?
Yes, keep reading. Mhm.
For the unbelieving husband is
sanctified by the wife, and the
unbelieving wife is sanctified by the
husband, else were your children
unclean, but now are they holy."
Uh-huh.
"But if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart. A brother or a sister is not
under bondage in such cases, but God has
called us to peace."
So, now
if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart.
Brother or sister is not
under bondage. In other words, you're
not obligated then to stay married to
him.
However,
got to be a non-believer. And if he's a
non-believer,
and if he's cheating on his wife, he's a
non-believer. He might be leaving not
leaving you physically, but he's leaving
you for a time to go out and live with
somebody else.
Now,
that's the best I can do with that.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one, Zion daughter asked for
explanation on Habakkuk 2:5.
Who is the man?
Habakkuk 2:5.
That's the book right before Zephaniah.
Right before Zephaniah.
So, Habakkuk 2:5.
When you get there, brother, go right
ahead. We're going to open that also to
the panel and she said, "Who is the
man?"
Yes.
Hey. All right. Habakkuk 2:5 says, "Yea,
also, because he transgresseth
by wine, he is a proud man, neither
keepeth at home, who enlargeth his
desires as hell,
and is as death, and cannot be
satisfied, but gathered unto him all
nations, and heaped unto him all
people."
All right. Open to the panel.
They want to know who is that man. It
says he is a proud man.
That's a man that refuse Any man that
refuse to be corrected by the Lord.
Yep.
And the correct answer.
Bad place to be. You started at the top
of the When you start at the top of the
scripture at verse one,
you know, it will tell you.
Mhm. Yep.
Okay. Verse one says, "I will stand upon
my watch, and set me upon the tower, and
will watch to see what he will say unto
me, and what I shall answer when I am
reproved. When I am When I am reproved,
that's anybody. Go ahead.
And the Lord answered me, and said,
write the vision, and make it plain upon
tables, that he may run that readeth it.
For the vision is yet and at yet for an
appointed time, but at the end it shall
speak and not lie.
Though it tarry, wait for it. Because it
will surely come, it will not tarry.
One more.
Behold, his soul which is lifted up is
not upright in him, but the just shall
live by his faith. And that's anybody.
But if any man would not be reproved,
then hey,
that's his that's his pride.
Yeah, that's what it says with lifted
up. Yeah, that mean he's proud in his
own man.
So, but he said but shall live by faith.
Faith in what? The word of God. He shall
walk in God's laws.
For there's any man.
Yeah.
All right.
Our next question.
Next one. Danielle Wellington says, I
heard that Valentine's Day is a pagan
holiday. If so, where can I find it in
the Bible?
I've never seen Valentine's Day in the
Bible, nor little babies riding around
in diapers with bow and arrows. Yeah.
And it's a day that celebrates a guy
that they call Saint Valentine.
Ask her what makes him a saint.
And who sanctified him?
Do a little history on what he's all
about.
You find out a little bit more about it.
It comes out of the Catholic Church.
That is right.
Full of paganism.
Yeah.
They just put
Just call
And this talks about the Catholic
Church. Let's go into
Revelation 17th chapter. Start reading
at verse one. Yes, sir. Okay.
Revelation 17 and verse one says,
"And there came one of the seven angels
which had the seven vials and talked
with me saying unto me, come hither. I
will show unto thee the judgment of the
great that sitteth upon many
waters.
With whom the kings of the earth have
committed fornication and the
inhabitants of the earth have been made
drunk with the wine of her fornication."
So he carried me Okay.
The
the wine of her fornication
is the doctrine. Go ahead.
"So he carried me away in the spirit
into the wilderness. And I saw a woman
sit upon a scarlet-colored beast full of
names of blasphemy, having seven heads
and 10 horns.
And the woman was arrayed in purple and
scarlet color and decked with gold and
precious stones and pearls, having a cup
in her hand full of abominations and
filthiness of her fornication.
And upon her forehead
Go ahead. And upon her forehead was a
name written, mystery, Babylon the
Great, the mother of harlots and
abomination of the earth."
And not not only is she is a false
church, you got a whole lot of other
little churches come out of her.
Now, let's go and show you where she got
her power from.
Let's back up to Revelation 13 chapter
and start reading at verse 1.
Okay.
Revelation 13 and verse 1 says,
"And I stood upon the sand of the sea.
And I saw a beast rise up out of the sea
having seven heads and 10 horns.
And upon her horns 10 crowns. And upon
his heads the name of blasphemy."
"And the
And the beast which I saw was like unto
a leopard. And his feet were as the feet
of a bear. And his mouth as the mouth of
a lion. And the dragon gave him his
power and his seat and great authority."
So, now, this is talking about the same
one, that woman.
That's riding that beast.
Where do he get Where do he get the
power from? Satan the devil. And that
woman is the Catholic Church and she is
the one that got all these saints. Saint
Valentine.
And for Christmas, Saint Nicholas. Okay?
Yep.
And so on and so on. The Lord said,
"Hey,
they got their power from Satan the
devil." And that cup got a golden cup in
her hand. The nations been made drunk
out of that cup. That mean
that what's what's come out of that cup?
Christmas, booze, Easter, Saint
Valentine,
uh going to heaven. All of that stuff
was taught by the Catholic Church.
And she is the mother of harlots. That's
why she called herself the mother
church.
The ones that come out of her are called
Protestants.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
Hope that answered your question. Our
next one.
Uh yes, Charlie wants you to explain
how the Gentiles and others can be
adopted in with Israel. Will they have
to keep the royal law and holy feasts
first?
Isaiah 56 chapter
Yeah.
Even verse one.
Okay.
Isaiah 56
and verse one says,
"Thus saith the Lord,
keep ye judgment, and do justice: for my
salvation is near to come, and my
righteousness to be revealed.
Blessed is the man that doeth this, and
the son of man that layeth hold on it.
That keepeth the Sabbath from polluting
it, and keeping his hand from doing any
evil."
It said a man and the son of man that do
this. That keep the Sabbath from
polluting it and his hand from doing any
evil. Go ahead.
Neither let the son of the stranger,
that is joined himself to the Lord,
speak, saying,
"The Lord hath utterly separated me from
his people: neither let the eunuch say,
Behold, I am a tree a dry tree."
We're not worried about the eunuch, but
it said the son of the stranger that
joined himself to the Lord. Said
I don't want him to say the Lord has
totally separated me from his people.
Skip down to verse six and let's see
what he said about the stranger.
Also, the sons of the stranger, that
join themselves to the Lord, to serve
him, and to love the name of the Lord,
to be his servants everyone that keepeth
the Sabbath from polluting it, and
taking hold of my covenant.
Even them
Mhm. and take the
uncircumcised and take a hold of my
covenant. Go ahead and read.
Even them will I bring to my holy
mountain
and make them joyful in my house of
prayer.
Their burnt offerings and their
sacrifices shall be accepted upon mine
altar.
For mine house shall be called an house
of prayer for all people.
Okay.
Finish it and read the next verse.
The Lord God, which hath gathered the
outcasts of Israel, saith yet will I
gather others to him besides those that
are gathered unto him.
Do not. They surely they have to keep
that, but they have to keep it all. Now,
let's go to Genesis the 17th chapter.
And we going to read he said take a hold
of his covenant. Didn't he say that?
Yes, sir.
>> Okay, let's look at this covenant he was
talking about. So, okay, you had a
covenant inside of our covenant.
Let's see uh
This is my covenant which he shall keep
between me and thee and thy seed after
thee.
Verse 10, sir.
What verse is that? Verse 10.
Go ahead and read it.
This is my covenant which he shall keep
between me and you and thy seed after
thee.
Every man child among you shall be
circumcised.
Right.
And ye shall circumcise the flesh of
your foreskin and it shall be a token of
the covenant betwixt me and you.
Uh-huh.
And he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you.
Every man-child in your generations, he
that is born in the house or bought with
money of any stranger which is not of
thy seed.
Uh-huh.
He that is born in thine house and he
that is that is bought with thy money
must needs be circumcised.
And my covenant
Mhm. Let's
You know, that's that's that that bought
with money represent being purchased
with the blood of Jesus. For my word,
keep reading.
>> And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for everlasting covenant.
Uh-huh. And the uncircumcised man-child
whose flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul shall be cut off
from his people. He has broken my
covenant.
Now, that's the stranger and Israel. One
of the things we need Go to look at
that. Somebody grab it right quick where
it say the commonwealth of Israel.
In the New Testament.
Ephesians 2
Okay. Go read it. Two and what?
Let me get it.
All right. Let me search modes. We find
it in that shortly.
>> feet
Yeah.
Yeah, bro.
>> want to back up a little bit. Okay.
Um
Start it. Should have started 10.
Yeah, go ahead, bro.
For verse 10, Ephesians 2 and 10. Okay,
verse Ephesians 2 and 11 says,
"Wherefore remember that ye being in
time past Gentiles in the flesh who are
called uncircumcision
by that which is called the circumcision
in the flesh made by hands.
That at that time you were without
Christ, being aliens from the
Commonwealth of Israel and strangers
from the covenants of promise, having no
hope and without God in the world.
Now, pay attention to what he said here.
And strangers from the covenants of God.
Isn't that what it said?
Yes, sir.
But look what happened now. Keep
reading.
But now, in Christ Jesus, ye who
sometimes were far off, are made nigh by
the blood of Christ.
Go ahead.
For he is our peace, who hath made both
one and hath broken down the middle wall
of partition between us.
Uh-huh.
Having abolished in his flesh the
enmity, even the law of commandments
contained in ordinances, for to make in
himself of twain one new man, so making
peace.
Okay.
Go ahead.
>> And Mhm.
And that he might reconcile both unto
God in one body by the cross, having
slain the enmity thereby.
Now, that's why you become a part of the
Commonwealth of Israel. And we're going
to read one more place and we'll leave
it alone.
Let's go on to
Galatians the third chapter, because it
said before Christ,
you know, they didn't do uh uh uh
Gentiles separated and they should not
have been.
Galatians the third chapter.
And we're going to start uh reading at
uh verse 27.
27 to 29. Okay.
Galatians 3 chapter uh uh
6 to 29.
Okay. Galatians 3 verse
says, "For ye are all the children of
God by faith in Christ Jesus.
For as For as many of you as have been
baptized into Christ have put on Christ.
There is neither Jew nor Greek. There is
neither bond nor free. There is neither
male nor female for ye are all one in
Christ Jesus.
And if ye be Christ, then are ye
Abraham's seed and heirs according to
the promise."
Do now, what did Abraham's seed have to
do?
Be circumcised. Be circumcised. Mhm.
Everything You can become spiritual
Abraham's seed or spiritually Israel,
but everything that God gave Abraham and
Israel to do,
if you're a stranger, that is you're a
Gentile, a Hamite, a
Semitic that didn't come out of Israel,
you got to do the exact same thing.
That's all I have to say.
Yes, sir.
Even at Exodus 12:49 says, "One law
shall be to him that is homeborn and
unto the stranger that sojourneth among
you." Yes, sir.
>> read the same thing in Ephesians the
fourth chapter.
All right, Sister Deborah. We're going
to take it to a time check.
Yes, the time is 9:05.
All right, we have ran out of time. We
want to thank everybody from around the
world who sent in their questions. If
you sent in a question we didn't get to
it, don't resubmit it cuz Sister Deborah
will take your question, put it in
rotation, and we will address that
question next Wednesday. So, until we
all come together again, be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
James closes us out.
Our
which art in heaven, hallowed be thy
name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil for
thine is the kingdom and the power and
the glory forever. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.